<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2016s on A Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2016s on A Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 18:20:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Managed File Transfer Shenanigans</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/managed_file_transfer_shenanigans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 18:20:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/managed_file_transfer_shenanigans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;An approach in integrating two systems which I see pretty regularly is to take
an old, or legacy file format and copy it over to another system.  The end goal
being that you would write some kind of parser on the receiving end of this file
to take and ingest that format in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is your Poor Man&amp;rsquo;s Service Oriented Architecture, where systems either
don&amp;rsquo;t have integration endpoints, or the work to implement all of those are
deemed too difficult and/or time consuming.  I don&amp;rsquo;t fault anyone for wanting to
keep an old system alive (ROI is a powerful thing when it works), but having
been thrown in this pit of non-web services&amp;rsquo; integration, you must be aware of
several considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;timing-guarantees-missed-arrivals-late-deliveries-etc&#34;&gt;Timing Guarantees, Missed Arrivals, Late Deliveries, etc.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you implement any form of &lt;code&gt;cron&lt;/code&gt;-based scheduling, you need to keep a very
clearly defined processes to handle contingencies in any of the following
issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failed Job Runs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missed Delivery Timeframes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late Delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duplicate Delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any one of which can create mountains of trouble for you and your system.  How
you go about verifying any of the above is somewhat dependent on the use-case of
the system and the requirements that are being fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;failed-job-runs&#34;&gt;Failed Job Runs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For failures, you&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; an alerting system to provide at least some
guarantee that you&amp;rsquo;ll know when things need to be recovered or automatically
retried.  Scheduling a re-run of failed jobs has it&amp;rsquo;s own issues, and there are
who-knows-how-many systems out there that can provide some kind of scheduling
toolkit for you to use.  Aim for the automatic if possible, as it&amp;rsquo;s always
faster for the system to retry for you than have you try to do it at 2AM or 3AM
in the morning (these jobs never fail at 9AM or after your second cup of
coffee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;late-delivery&#34;&gt;Late Delivery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s really two forms of this error&amp;ndash;early and late delivery.  I have seldom
seen a system that had a problem with early delivery, and if it happens, it
usually just means the data isn&amp;rsquo;t completely available or full.  I would like to
focus on Late Delivery, however, as that seems much more commonplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late delivery can mean a lot of things for a system, such as not being able to
send a shipment out on time, not getting bills paid within some kind of Service
Level Guarantee, or even automatically kickstarting some backup or redundancy
processes that will attempt to re-run your job or re-process things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficulty in late- or long-running processes is knowing what will occur
that way.  In a future post, I&amp;rsquo;ll prescribe some methods to identify and fix
these issues.  For now, it&amp;rsquo;s important to just be aware of this situation when
debugging or developing an integration/file transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;duplicate-entry&#34;&gt;Duplicate Entry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you get in a vicious cycle of processing the same data over and over
again, there&amp;rsquo;s&amp;ndash;at minimum&amp;ndash;the added load of having your systems process extra
data without need.  Worse yet, if your data is naive enough to have data in the
form of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;--Add $20 to account X
--Subtract $100 from account X
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you re-process this data again and again, you&amp;rsquo;re going to have a bad day when
someone calls in to say that they lost all their money, or &lt;strong&gt;nobody&lt;/strong&gt; calls in
when they somehow accidentally got $$$$$&amp;rsquo;s of dollars without notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to build in some kind of tolerance for this, and hopefully that can be
encoded in the file you&amp;rsquo;re processing.  The ideal goal should be to make
re-processing&amp;ndash; at worst&amp;ndash;a wasted effort, and at best, no processing at all.
That can&amp;rsquo;t always be the case, but it should be strived for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;verification-and-validation&#34;&gt;Verification and Validation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What comes next is that when you get a file, you need to do both &lt;strong&gt;verify&lt;/strong&gt; that
it is the file you need, and &lt;strong&gt;validate&lt;/strong&gt; that it can be properly parsed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;verification&#34;&gt;Verification&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verification is the act of assuring that the file you&amp;rsquo;re looking at came from
the person or system you expected it to.  In broad terms, you should encrypt
files at rest, &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt;.  This isn&amp;rsquo;t going to cover everything, however,
because while it may prevent a man-in-the-middle attacker from subverting and/or
mucking with your system data, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t preclude a user from using a public
key to drop something else they&amp;rsquo;d like you to process, which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be
processed at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose to encrypt the file, you better be using some form of Digital
Signature.  It&amp;rsquo;s about the only means you have to verify that the person that
encrypted it was the person you wanted to get the file from.  I am not terribly
strong on this front, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of details on this, but it&amp;rsquo;s
something that&amp;rsquo;s getting a lot more attention with sites like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io&#34;&gt;Keybase.io&lt;/a&gt; and the general trend of using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blog/2144-gpg-signature-verification&#34;&gt;GPG-signed
commits, a la, GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;validation&#34;&gt;Validation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we get to the Validation portion of the file.  This is simply being
able to parse the file out properly before you attempt to import it in to the
system.  Many systems do this, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is a terribly difficult
part of the process to handle.  That said, I would avoid doing any kind of
transaction committal before processing the whole file.  The worst-case scenario
here is that you find that the file format isn&amp;rsquo;t quite right, or that something
is out of alignment (a huge issue with column-delimted or CSV data), so you will
find yourself inserting the wrong columns into your system without proper
validation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;File transfer as a service is hard.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s something that you can
take for granted as being &amp;lsquo;just a &lt;code&gt;cron&lt;/code&gt; job&amp;rsquo;, as it&amp;rsquo;s way more complicated than
that.  You will inevitably trip yourself up with any of these kinds of things.
I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say it&amp;rsquo;s less likely in the SOA or web services world, but the scope
of the problem is way larger when you batch things up into a file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seldom is a file just one record or transaction.  If you are at the point that
doing SOA or some kind of API development is an issue, you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself
inevitably bundling up as much as you can in that file, turning what would have
been a bunch of service calls into one massive file for import.  Now your
problem is compounded by having to not just be valid on the row or record-level,
but valid at the entire boundary of the file.  What happens if it&amp;rsquo;s incorrect?
Can you parse it out to find out where it broke?  How do you know the next file
will be correct?  Is there a way to reproduce the issue?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest that if you find yourself using file-based transfer systems a lot,
you&amp;rsquo;re probably solving the wrong problem.  You need to look at what you&amp;rsquo;re
taking in, how it&amp;rsquo;s being done, and just converting that into some kind of an
ETL tool or SOA integration.  Doing much else is just a recipe for the problems
above.  It&amp;rsquo;s bad enough that any of these would happen, let alone having to
safeguard yourself from all of them at once.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Company Benefits for Drilling Military Reservists</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/benefits_for_military/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/benefits_for_military/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The case for supporting your military with more than a yellow ribbon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies make a point to mention all of their benefits, touting how they
are &amp;lsquo;among the best&amp;rsquo;, or have &amp;lsquo;a competitive benefits package&amp;rsquo;.  This might be
true for the 80% case, but being an actively drilling Reservist in the United
States Army Reserve, there&amp;rsquo;s an obviously lacking set of benefits that appeal to
me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-drilling-reservist-guard-member&#34;&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;Drilling Reservist/Guard Member?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have heard the sales pitch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One weekend a month, two weeks a year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and think that&amp;rsquo;s pretty reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I thought, too, when I enlisted in 2004.  However, &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;11&lt;/sub&gt; was in 2001,
and since then, the contributions that the Reserve/Guard side of the military
have taken has increased &lt;strong&gt;significantly&lt;/strong&gt;, both in number of deployments, time
away from home for training, and increased tempo.  I know many people who have
served &lt;em&gt;multiple&lt;/em&gt; deployments of 6-18 months in a 5-10 year period.  That&amp;rsquo;s
a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me restate that I would &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; state that the Reserve/Guard side of the
house is doing more than the Active Duty side, nor should the increased number
of deployments detract away from what the Active Duty Soldiers, Sailors,
Marines, Airmen/women all contribute and have the same struggles.  That said,
when they retire from Active Duty service, they are a Veteran, and may also
continue to contribute their time to the Reserves or Guard.  While the treatment
of Veterans issues is a critical issue, it is somewhat separate from these
points, and something I would prefer to discuss separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;increased-tempo&#34;&gt;Increased Tempo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Drill Weekend&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Battle Assembly&lt;/em&gt; or whatever you call your weekend
requirements, is billed with the funny moniker, &lt;u&gt;&amp;hellip;one weekend a month&amp;hellip;&lt;/u&gt;
I would have to say that in my nearly 12 years in the Reserves, I have had
probably 4- or 5- weekends &lt;strong&gt;total&lt;/strong&gt; that fit that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                          11 years = 132 months
...one weekend a month... weekends = 4-5
                          the rest = 127-128 months
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the way that a weekend is counted is generally what you would call an
8-hour day.  In addition to saying these are billed as one-weekend affairs,
you&amp;rsquo;d think your day was a little longer.  I would say most weekends were at
least 12 hours, and I&amp;rsquo;ve gone without much more than 4-5 hours sleep in
a weekend in it&amp;rsquo;s entirety.  usually what we try to fit in these days.  It is
extremely difficult to meet the demands of the training requirements in an
8 hour day, and I would wager it is impossible without also requiring that
everyone does a bunch of work outside of the weekend to get things done (which
is also what happens, too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-constitutes-training&#34;&gt;What constitutes Training?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would you think fits in a normal weekend of training?  It is very often
completely different month-to-month, as we have a lot of general requirements to
meet in addition to the other training that we are required to fulfill.  Some of
these training events include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physical Fitness Tests (PT Test, PFT, etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marksmanship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MOS-based skills development (depends greatly on what your unit does)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team / Squad / Platoon / Company team building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandatory training (sexual assault / harrassment awareness, legal,
benefits, meet-and-greet with senior leadership)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say that it would be enough to just perform the MOS-based skills
development, but adding in these other requirements just makes things a whole
lot more difficult and time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extra-curricular-training&#34;&gt;Extra-curricular Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the &lt;strong&gt;minimum&lt;/strong&gt; requirements mentioned above, more often than
not, you may want to take on an additional training course or two in order to
stand out from your peers and potentially increase your knowledge and expertise
in your military occupational field/specialty (MOS). This is entirely possible,
but must happen completely outside of the time you&amp;rsquo;ve committed to the unit for
their training needs.  Your personal training needs are completely different,
and will require you to give up even more of your time.  There are a lot of
different training and extra time that you can commit yourself to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra Duty Service

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This would be where you would volunteer to help on a mini-mission of sorts,
something that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require an entire company to work on, but isn&amp;rsquo;t
something that can be done during the weekend.  It also could include
catch-up work that needed to be done but wasn&amp;rsquo;t complete before the
weekend, so could take a couple extra days out of your regular work-week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special Billet Training - leadership assignments that require additional training, such as:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equal Opportunity training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit Prevention Leader (qualified urinalysis test administrator training)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sexual Assault and Harassment representative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battle Assembly (learning to operate a unit&amp;rsquo;s admin house during
  a deployment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weapons Armorer (maintain the weapons)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership Advancement courses (often, these are required prerequisites before
you can even apply for a promotion to a Sergeant (SGT), Staff-Sergeant
(SSG), etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each one of these kinds of assignments can take anywhere from 1 to 4 weeks of
additional time during your year.  This is training that must be complete &lt;strong&gt;in
addition to&lt;/strong&gt; the unit&amp;rsquo;s required training.  If you have any hopes to be
a well-rounded leader, you will want to participate in these other training and
opportunities so you stand out a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-standard-training-cycles&#34;&gt;Non-Standard Training cycles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the above, you may start to realize that just meeting the &lt;u&gt;bare minimum&lt;/u&gt;
can be a big chore and requirement.  If you&amp;rsquo;re a leader for the unit, you&amp;rsquo;re
probably thinking &amp;ldquo;How the heck am I going to get this stuff done in
a weekend?&amp;rdquo; Well, the leaders have definitely thought about this, and what has
come down is to try to turn a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;hellip;one weekend a month&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt; into  &lt;strong&gt;&amp;hellip;three or
four days in a month&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A usual weekend for me is either a Friday - Sunday, or a Thursday through
Sunday.  This gives ample time to devote every hour of those days towards some
form of training.  We do a lot of training, but we also try to maximize the fact
that we have a captive audience, so we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;strong&gt;dare&lt;/strong&gt; send someone home after
a mere 8- or 12- hour day.  No, we will go from 5AM to 10PM every day to try to
fit in as much as possible.  If you can&amp;rsquo;t do the calculation in your head,
that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;u&gt;17 hours a day&lt;/u&gt;.  Long days, for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-does-supporting-the-troops-mean-anyway&#34;&gt;What does &amp;ldquo;Supporting the Troops&amp;rdquo; mean, anyway?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;strong&gt;Support the Troops&lt;/strong&gt; is very, VERY often, thrown about without any
regard for &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to do that.  I can only speak as a Reservist, so Active Duty
members may have a different opinion on the matter.  That said, I deal with
civilians daily, so I am often the face of the military for many people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to think that support means the same thing if you&amp;rsquo;re looking at it from
paternity / maternity leave, as well as different kinds of support you might
provide an employee when they&amp;rsquo;re going through a rough patch, such as a divorce,
death in the family, etc..  You might be a little more lenient on time away, or
you might try to provide them some things to make their days a little easier to
bear.  I think the same kind of empathy should be provided for someone who
chooses to commit &lt;strong&gt;one weekend a month&lt;/strong&gt;* to serving your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am certainly burned out after a long drill weekend, but I also have a very
hard time trying to stay on top of my career while also giving way to the
requirements of having to show up for my military obligations as well.  It&amp;rsquo;s
a tough set of things to do, and that isn&amp;rsquo;t even mentioning any kind of family
life you may have at home.  I know that my time with my family is critically
important to me, so having that flexibility to spend time with them is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;benefits-for-reservists&#34;&gt;Benefits for Reservists&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the benefits I look at as a potential employee, none stands out more than
whether you have any policy defined &lt;strong&gt;at all&lt;/strong&gt; for drilling members of the
military.  These benefts vary, but generally speaking, the biggest one is
simply:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;salary-continuity&#34;&gt;Salary Continuity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes all &lt;em&gt;training&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;monthly drill weekends&lt;/em&gt;, activation (when
necessary), and additional training as required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;make it obvious that your employment isn&amp;rsquo;t in jeopardy if you choose to do more
than the minimum required by contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, being able to provide continuity to your salary and family&amp;rsquo;s life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;avoid-bean-counting&#34;&gt;Avoid Bean Counting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that there are companies that are willing to provide that above
requirement, but they may do so on a limited basis.  They may allot X days
a month or a year to contribute to this fund, but no more.  Given what I have
said above, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s being honest about what your average military
Reservist is having to contribute, and it forces them to choose between being
a mediocre member of the military to one of the better ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe there should be any limitation to the time spent away.  If you
believe they are valuable as an employee, it is because of what they do, not in
spite of it.  It is probably difficult to compensate for someone that is not
there, and doubly so when you may have to hire someone to backfill for when
you&amp;rsquo;re out.  However, I think you hired the person because of their skills and
ability, so you should recognize that you&amp;rsquo;re essentially paying a small tax on
the benefit of having someone of that calibur working with your company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Formatting and Parallelism</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/trackello_parallelism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 16:25:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/trackello_parallelism/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;improved-formatting-in-trackello&#34;&gt;Improved Formatting in Trackello&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klauern/trackello&#34;&gt;trackello&lt;/a&gt; app for
a few weeks and I do like the way I can keep track of my work.  However, some of
the things I was curious about were more specific to the card.  If you&amp;rsquo;ve used
this application, you may have noticed that activity is marked by repeated
entries of the same card.  This is just messy, and not something that I thought
would be usable if you had a particularly busy week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remedy this, I set about fixing it up with some additional fields:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.nickklauer.info/img/trackello_colorized.png&#34; alt=&#34;trackello&#34; title=&#34;Trackello with statistics&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I added a placeholder for some general-purpose statistics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.nickklauer.info/img/trackello_statistics.png&#34; alt=&#34;statistics&#34; title=&#34;Statistics in Trackello&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a very solid setup for how I want to layer this out at this time,
but it provides a lot more information for a particular card than before.  Now,
with a quick glance you can get a rough estimate on how much you&amp;rsquo;ve been
fiddling with a particular card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;parallelism&#34;&gt;Parallelism&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I added this in, I had to make some changes in terms of collecting the
actions for a board and being able to parse it out.  For whatever reason, I was
initially going about it in a very naive way, requesting a card or list for
&lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; action that I had.  This resulted in a couple issues off the bat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many actions result in many HTTP requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duplicating the same &lt;code&gt;HTTP GET&lt;/code&gt; for the same card multiple times was
redundant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each call was done in succession of the previous one, in order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first attempted to at least simplify how many calls I was making, ensuring
I was only making calls when I needed new information (such as a new Card that
I had not yet encountered).  However, that didn&amp;rsquo;t really speed things up, and
I found that it would wait 20-30 seconds just to return a Board&amp;rsquo;s Actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I pursued one of the things that Go is known for&amp;ndash;easy parallelism with
Goroutines.  I am not an expert in this stuff, but managed to wing it somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using parallelism in Go is a lot easier than I intially thought it would be.
That isn&amp;rsquo;t to say it&amp;rsquo;s not fraught with concurrency issues, but it seems that
the scope of the issues is contained well enough that you can work out a lot of
the things that I used to get hung up on for DAYS with Java Threads and
concurrency there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a quick comparison, but the performance improvement is noticable
off the bat, so I&amp;rsquo;m pretty confident in sticking with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;future-work&#34;&gt;Future work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to use this framework and library as the basis for something a little
more interesting.  I know that Trello is great for building a lot of different
kinds of sites, and one thing that I was really interested in is how &lt;a href=&#34;https://changelog.com&#34;&gt;The
Changelog&lt;/a&gt; uses Trello to build their weekly email.
I figure I can probably build something similar in Go and share it with the
world.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know if there&amp;rsquo;s another project out there for it, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t
yet been able to find one, so there&amp;rsquo;s an opening.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trackello</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/trackello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 20:31:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/trackello/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;trello-s-api-and-golang&#34;&gt;Trello&amp;rsquo;s API and Golang&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among some of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/netgearlogs&#34;&gt;my&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.nickklauer.info/2015/announcing_remy&#34;&gt;earlier&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.nickklauer.info/2015/thoughts_on_go&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking towards Golang
as a tool for building some more command-line apps.  To better understand how to
use it for HTTP-based client work, I wanted to build a small command-line app to
work with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.trello.com/&#34;&gt;Trello API&lt;/a&gt;.  When working with it, I found a really excellent
Golang API for the Trello API here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/VojtechVitek/go-trello&#34;&gt;https://github.com/VojtechVitek/go-trello&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;trackello&#34;&gt;Trackello&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, my boss wanted to get a bi-weekly update of projects, tasks, and
things I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on.  This was more for him to have an idea what I was
putting my time into, as well as having evidence for promotions, bonuses, etc.
I track most of my work using Trello, so this seemed a perfect opportunity to
pull all of this information out using the built-in &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.trello.com/&#34;&gt;Trello API&lt;/a&gt; that they so
wonderfully provided us users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, let us introduce to the audience, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klauern/trackello/&#34;&gt;Trackello&lt;/a&gt;, a CLI to track your
work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;Trackello is a command-line tool to allow you to retrieve and get
information on your Trello boards.  This tool provides a list
of the previous 14 days of information on a board defined in
your &#39;config&#39; file (see &#39;--config&#39; flag for info

Usage:
  trackello [command]

Available Commands:
  boards      List all of your boards
  cards       List all of the cards on a particular board.
  config      Configure your Trello API keys and preferred Trello Board
  list        List activities on a board

Flags:
      --appkey string   Trello Application Key
      --board string    Preferred Board ID
      --config string   config file (default is $HOME/.trackello.yaml)
  -h, --help            help for trackello
      --token string    Trello Token

Use &amp;quot;trackello [command] --help&amp;quot; for more information about a command.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To talk to the Trello API, you need two pieces:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trello APP key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trello Token&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get both of these, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com/app-key&#34;&gt;https://trello.com/app-key&lt;/a&gt; .  You can get both the
Application key and a personal Token.  For my first iteration of this program, I
assumed you would want to get information for &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; Trello board, which would
be your /preferred/ board.  This is not required for normal use, but makes things
easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, the command-line options can help here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ trackello help config
Using config file: /&amp;lt;your_home_dir&amp;gt;/.trackello.yaml
To communicate to a Trello API, you will need to configure a
minimum of 3 parameters:
  - TRELLO_APPKEY
  - TRELLO_TOKEN
  - preferredBoard

If you do not know or have any of these, you can review  the documentation
on this site: https://trello.com/app-key

Usage:
  trackello config [flags]

Global Flags:
      --appkey string   Trello Application Key
      --board string    Preferred Board ID
      --config string   config file (default is $HOME/.trackello.yaml)
      --token string    Trello Token
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you call this command and pass in the Global Flags, you will get
a &lt;code&gt;trackello.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file that has your configuration in it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;$ cat ~/.trackello.yaml
appkey: f3ff39c83d227a7243abf4df66ffffff
token: b448d5fb4f1af85f3fffffffffffffffffffffffffffffffffffffffffffffff
board: 572ffff7ffffffffffffff83
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;listing-a-specific-board-s-actions&#34;&gt;Listing A Specific Board&amp;rsquo;s Actions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the &lt;code&gt;trackello list&lt;/code&gt; command will show you a listing of all board
actions that occured in the last two weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;listing-all-boards&#34;&gt;Listing All Boards&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, you can also list all of your boards using &lt;code&gt;trackello boards&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 9 Modularity Features</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/jlinker-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 19:47:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/jlinker-demo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;modularity-in-the-jvm&#34;&gt;Modularity in the JVM&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent some time yesterday playing with the demos for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/projects/jigsaw/quick-start&#34;&gt;Jigsaw Project&lt;/a&gt;,
and have something that I hope is usable for others:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klauern/modularity&#34;&gt;github.com/klauern/modularity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet tried it on a Windows machine, but that&amp;rsquo;s next on my list.  Each
of the examples in the Jigsaw Quick Start have an associated &lt;code&gt;run.sh&lt;/code&gt; script
that will build the example.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t done much documenting, but I do suggest
that if you&amp;rsquo;re looking at these examples, you follow along with the
documentation.  It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, and does a much better job explaining the
steps than I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jlinker-sizes&#34;&gt;JLinker sizes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest reason I wanted to play with the Jigsaw features was to see how the
&lt;code&gt;jlink&lt;/code&gt;er worked in terms of generating a self-contained JVM+runnable app.  I&amp;rsquo;m
pretty happy with it, and think that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty slick, all things considered.
The downside is just the size.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure that it&amp;rsquo;s a massive effort to slim down
the JVM to what is absolutely needed to run the code you have, but the smallest
example I could run on my MacBook Air was around ~33MB.  That&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, but
still pretty large (at least compared to a similarly-written Golan project).
I think that things are probably trending even further downward, so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t
be surprised to see further interations of this slim it down further, or even
finding some excited hackers able to shrink it even further themselves.  At this
point, I&amp;rsquo;m really hopeful, and think that this is a pretty nice addition the
JVM.  More competition is always a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 9 and Jigsaw improvements with &#39;jlink&#39;</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/jdk-9-linker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 13:01:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/jdk-9-linker/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It was &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mreinhold/status/713384458452226048&#34;&gt;recently announced&lt;/a&gt;
that Java 9&amp;rsquo;s latest builds now include the Project Jigsaw module system.  This
is pretty awesome stuff, to be honest.  One of the benefits that a lot of
systems-programming advocates claim is having a self-hosted runtime.  Being able
to do that is at least feasable in Jigsaw, using the built-in &lt;code&gt;jlink&lt;/code&gt; tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate that it will completely replace the JDK for some
applicaitons, but it brings in a whole new world of options.  Some features I&amp;rsquo;m
pretty interested in include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved dynamic language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pre-compilation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;selective runtime includes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;faster bootstrap/startup times, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;likely a whole new host of self-bootstrapping desktop/server applications that
don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry nearly as much about having to roll in an entire runtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of good resources that I scoured trying to build this, so I&amp;rsquo;ll
link to them here in case you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn for yourself or just have some fun
times digging around the docs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mreinhold.org/blog/jigsaw-modular-images&#34;&gt;Project Jigsaw: Modular run-time images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/projects/jigsaw/quick-start&#34;&gt;Project Jigsaw: Module System Quick-Start Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jdk9.java.net/download/&#34;&gt;JDK 9 Early Access Releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l1s7R85GF1A&#34;&gt;Keynote Session: Mark Reinhold (covers Jigsaw)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started-guide-for-jigsaw&#34;&gt;Getting Started Guide for Jigsaw&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that build 111+ has support for Jigsaw, we should be able to follow their
&lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/projects/jigsaw/quick-start&#34;&gt;Module System Quick-Start Guide&lt;/a&gt;
and get things rolling.  I&amp;rsquo;ve started out building this Quick-Start guide
and have put it on GitHub: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klauern/modularity&#34;&gt;https://github.com/klauern/modularity&lt;/a&gt; . I can&amp;rsquo;t
say that I have everything working, but I am pleased that things are working as
smoothly as they are, considering this is&amp;ndash;at best&amp;ndash;an alpha release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-posts&#34;&gt;Future Posts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have everything in a demo-able state, but I&amp;rsquo;m working on things and may
have more to update as that above repository is updated.  Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JVM GC Log Parsing</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/jvmgc-log-parsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/jvmgc-log-parsing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Along the same lines as my &lt;a href=&#34;../netgearlogs&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I had a need to
analyze a set of JVM Garbage Collector logs for event types.  Consider a log
entry like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;2016-02-11T23:39:01.847-0600: 6062789.760: [GC2016-02-11T23:39:01.848-0600: 6062789.761: [ParNew
Desired survivor size 178946048 bytes, new threshold 15 (max 15)
- age   1:    3565648 bytes,    3565648 total
- age   2:     278800 bytes,    3844448 total
- age   3:    1203288 bytes,    5047736 total
- age   4:      33184 bytes,    5080920 total
- age   5:    1717432 bytes,    6798352 total
- age   6:    1673032 bytes,    8471384 total
- age   7:     792920 bytes,    9264304 total
- age   8:     275424 bytes,    9539728 total
- age   9:     262384 bytes,    9802112 total
- age  10:     517584 bytes,   10319696 total
- age  11:       4576 bytes,   10324272 total
- age  12:     444104 bytes,   10768376 total
- age  13:      32080 bytes,   10800456 total
- age  14:     512392 bytes,   11312848 total
- age  15:     359904 bytes,   11672752 total
: 1416735K-&amp;gt;15751K(1747648K), 0.0379220 secs] 4798752K-&amp;gt;3399739K(8039104K), 0.0384330 secs] [Times: user=0.00 sys=0.32, real=0.04 secs]
Heap
 par new generation   total 1747648K, used 1145132K [0x00000005a0000000, 0x0000000620000000, 0x0000000620000000)
  eden space 1398144K,  80% used [0x00000005a0000000, 0x00000005e4ee9178, 0x00000005f5560000)
  from space 349504K,   4% used [0x000000060aab0000, 0x000000060ba11eb8, 0x0000000620000000)
  to   space 349504K,   0% used [0x00000005f5560000, 0x00000005f5560000, 0x000000060aab0000)
 concurrent mark-sweep generation total 6291456K, used 3383987K [0x0000000620000000, 0x00000007a0000000, 0x00000007a0000000)
 concurrent-mark-sweep perm gen total 941872K, used 553029K [0x00000007a0000000, 0x00000007d97cc000, 0x0000000800000000)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of log entry is far from simple to understand.  I could go about
hand-writing another parser, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it would be anywhere near the
same level of complexity.  In fact, for the most part, all I really wanted to
know was the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016-02-11T23:39:01.847-0600&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;6062789.760&lt;/strong&gt;: [GC2016-02-11T23:39:01.848-0600: 6062789.761: [&lt;strong&gt;ParNew&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to parse much else from the get-go seemed a bit much, and there&amp;rsquo;s
a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of output that I&amp;rsquo;d have to skip around just to find these entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not knowing where to look, I threw a question out to one of my favorite go-to
tools for parsing JVM logs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chewiebug/GCViewer&#34;&gt;GCViewer&lt;/a&gt;.
There must be &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; that you can use in there to parse out a log entry.
Reaching out to the developer in an issue, I was able to get pointed in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chewiebug/GCViewer/issues/164#issuecomment-195405552&#34;&gt;right direction&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Nick,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see two options to get the information for your alerting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use the command-line interface of GCViewer to generate a CSV file
 containing a lot of information (java -jar gcviewer-1.3x.jar gc.log
 summary.csv) -&amp;gt; parse the csv file and extract the information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;java/com/tagtraum/perf/gcviewer/imp/DataReaderFacade.java&lt;/code&gt; and use
 the resulting GCModel to extract the information you are looking for for
 the alerts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best regards,
Jörg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at #2, and found that this makes parsing a log file relatively
painless, and gives you a lot in the way of structural analysis of the logs
themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-gcviewer-for-log-parsing-as-an-api&#34;&gt;Using GCViewer for Log Parsing as an API&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;package klauern;

import com.tagtraum.perf.gcviewer.imp.DataReaderException;
import com.tagtraum.perf.gcviewer.imp.DataReaderFacade;
import com.tagtraum.perf.gcviewer.model.*;

import java.util.Iterator;

public class EventParser {

    public static void main(String[] args) throws DataReaderException {
        System.out.println(&amp;quot;Getting DataReader facade&amp;quot;);
        DataReaderFacade drf = new DataReaderFacade();
        System.out.println(&amp;quot;Loading model&amp;quot;);
        GCModel model = drf.loadModel(new GCResource(&amp;quot;src/test/resources/gc-log.current&amp;quot;));
        System.out.println(&amp;quot;Model Loaded&amp;quot;);

        System.out.println(&amp;quot;List Full GC Events:\n&amp;quot;);
        Iterator&amp;lt;GCEvent&amp;gt; full_gcs = model.getFullGCEvents();
        while (full_gcs.hasNext()) {
            GCEvent event = full_gcs.next();
            System.out.println(&amp;quot;Date: &amp;quot; + event.getDatestamp() + &amp;quot; Pause: &amp;quot; + event.getPause());
        }
        System.out.println(&amp;quot;List stop the world events:\n&amp;quot;);
        Iterator&amp;lt;AbstractGCEvent&amp;lt;?&amp;gt;&amp;gt; stw_events = model.getStopTheWorldEvents();
        while (stw_events.hasNext()) {
            AbstractGCEvent&amp;lt;?&amp;gt; event = stw_events.next();
            System.out.println(&amp;quot;Type: &amp;quot; + event.getTypeAsString() + &amp;quot; Date: &amp;quot; + event.getDatestamp() + &amp;quot; Pause: &amp;quot; + event.getPause());
        }

        System.out.println(&amp;quot;List CMS GC events&amp;quot;);
        Iterator&amp;lt;ConcurrentGCEvent&amp;gt; cms_gc_events = model.getConcurrentGCEvents();
        while (cms_gc_events.hasNext()) {
            ConcurrentGCEvent event = cms_gc_events.next();
            System.out.println(&amp;quot;Date: &amp;quot; + event.getDatestamp() + &amp;quot; Pause: &amp;quot; + event.getPause());
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just so simple, you have a lot at your fingertips.  Running this little
sample code on one of my example JVM logs produces the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Getting datareader facade
Loading model
Model Loaded
List Full GC Events:

List stop the world events:

Type: GC; ParNew Date: 2016-02-11T10:46:54.607-06:00 Pause: 0.058497
Type: GC; ParNew Date: 2016-02-11T10:47:34.438-06:00 Pause: 0.060133
Type: GC; ParNew Date: 2016-02-11T10:47:54.505-06:00 Pause: 0.057339
Type: GC; ParNew Date: 2016-02-11T10:47:56.742-06:00 Pause: 0.042955
.... # continues for a while
List CMS GC events
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:21.175-06:00 Pause: 0.0
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:23.193-06:00 Pause: 2.018
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:23.193-06:00 Pause: 0.0
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:23.231-06:00 Pause: 0.036
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:23.231-06:00 Pause: 0.0
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:28.254-06:00 Pause: 4.912
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:29.004-06:00 Pause: 0.0
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:34.463-06:00 Pause: 3.232
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:34.463-06:00 Pause: 0.0
Date: 2016-02-11T15:04:34.491-06:00 Pause: 0.028
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this point, I can really pull together some good statistics on frequency,
rate of growth, high-activity, and create those smell tests that you wish you
knew before something blew up in your face.  In my work experience, it&amp;rsquo;s not
often that people do enough testing with production-sized loads, or if they do,
they underestimate what those load look like.  It&amp;rsquo;s the worst possible scenario
to have poor performance only in your production environment, as it is
a possible indicator that these kind of GC-related events were present in your
testing but were completely missed or avoided because they weren&amp;rsquo;t visible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with NetGear Router Logs</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/netgearlogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 11:26:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/netgearlogs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I was recently toying around on my router and noticed that I can send myself
a set of logs related to activity going on.  Considering this an interesting
set of diagnostics, I thought it would be fun to create some way to parse these
log entries and save them in some format.  In addition, as I am also always
trying out new languages, the current language du jour is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org&#34;&gt;Golang&lt;/a&gt;, so it seems like a reasonably interesting problem
to solve in a library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-netgear-log-entries&#34;&gt;Example NetGear Log Entries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parsing a log seems like a fun diversion, and looking at the NetGear log format,
it seems apparent that there was little formality in how they even logged what
happened.  There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;some&lt;/strong&gt; structure to it, but it&amp;rsquo;s kinda messy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[DoS Attack: ACK Scan] from source: 195.179.119.177, port 80, Monday, February 22, 2016 04:42:22
[Internet connected] IP address: 127.0.0.1, Monday, February 22, 2016 09:02:59
[DHCP IP: 192.168.1.11] to MAC address ff:ff:ff:ff:ff:ff, Monday, February 22, 2016 06:15:56
[UPnP set event: del_nat_rule] from source 192.168.1.8, Saturday, February 20, 2016 19:27:21
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see that while it seems like everything within the square braces (&lt;code&gt;[]&lt;/code&gt;)
is simple, things like &lt;code&gt;DHCP IP: 192.168.1.11&lt;/code&gt; seem like a mixture of a rule
type and a dynamic piece of data.  Parsing this isn&amp;rsquo;t like parsing a regular
format, or at least, it has enough special rules that will make creating
a parser a bit more work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;parsing-logs&#34;&gt;Parsing Logs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struck out to solve this in a couple ways.  My first attempt was a very simple
attempt to brute-force the log by &lt;code&gt;switch&lt;/code&gt;&amp;lsquo;ing on a prefix, using some kind
of parsing for each type of log entry.  You can find example code of this on my
GitHub project here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klauern/go-netgearlogs/blob/master/netgear.go&#34;&gt;github.com/klauern/go-netgearlogs/netgear.go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly like the repetitive nature of it, but I wonder whether this
isn&amp;rsquo;t just &amp;lsquo;acceptable code duplication&amp;rsquo; due to the nature of Go not allowing
much in the way of abstraction.  That said, this works, and it throws everything
I have given it into my generic &lt;code&gt;NetGear&lt;/code&gt; struct type.  Yay for progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-s-parsing-strategies&#34;&gt;Go&amp;rsquo;s Parsing Strategies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After throwing together the above example, I started doing a bit more digging
and trying to determine if there was a &amp;ldquo;Go Way&amp;rdquo; to do things.  This is where
I stumbled on an article I was really excited about reading on the topic:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.gopheracademy.com/advent-2014/parsers-lexers/&#34;&gt;Handwritten Parsers &amp;amp; Lexers in Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the above blog as a guide, I struck out to create another format of the
parsing, to see if it would turn out to be simpler and/or more flexible. Currently,
I have some files that are still in-progress, but feel MUCH more like
a real parsing attempt for my problem.  I took a lot of inspiration
(&lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; copying &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt;)  from this article, and the current result can be
found in the source below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klauern/go-netgearlogs/blob/master/token.go&#34;&gt;github.com/klauern/go-netgearlogs/token.go&lt;/a&gt; (my list of tokens for a NetGear Log)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klauern/go-netgearlogs/blob/master/scanner.go&#34;&gt;github.com/klauern/go-netgearlogs/scanner.go&lt;/a&gt; (scanner for tokenizing the input into something above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klauern/go-netgearlogs/blob/master/parser.go&#34;&gt;github.com/klauern/go-netgearlogs/parser.go&lt;/a&gt; (parser for converting those tokens into something tangible)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is still a work-in-progress, but I highly recommend the blog post above if
you&amp;rsquo;re curious on writing your own parser.  I also recommend finding something
to write a parser for.  It really gives you a window into the world of text
processing, programming language design, etc., and I walked away with a lot of
knowledge on parsing that I did not have before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>