<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benefits on A Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/tags/benefits/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Benefits on A Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Nick Klauer</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.nickklauer.info/tags/benefits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Company Benefits for Drilling Military Reservists</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/benefits_for_military/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/2016/benefits_for_military/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The case for supporting your military with more than a yellow ribbon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies make a point to mention all of their benefits, touting how they
are &amp;lsquo;among the best&amp;rsquo;, or have &amp;lsquo;a competitive benefits package&amp;rsquo;.  This might be
true for the 80% case, but being an actively drilling Reservist in the United
States Army Reserve, there&amp;rsquo;s an obviously lacking set of benefits that appeal to
me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-drilling-reservist-guard-member&#34;&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;Drilling Reservist/Guard Member?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have heard the sales pitch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One weekend a month, two weeks a year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and think that&amp;rsquo;s pretty reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I thought, too, when I enlisted in 2004.  However, &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;11&lt;/sub&gt; was in 2001,
and since then, the contributions that the Reserve/Guard side of the military
have taken has increased &lt;strong&gt;significantly&lt;/strong&gt;, both in number of deployments, time
away from home for training, and increased tempo.  I know many people who have
served &lt;em&gt;multiple&lt;/em&gt; deployments of 6-18 months in a 5-10 year period.  That&amp;rsquo;s
a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me restate that I would &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; state that the Reserve/Guard side of the
house is doing more than the Active Duty side, nor should the increased number
of deployments detract away from what the Active Duty Soldiers, Sailors,
Marines, Airmen/women all contribute and have the same struggles.  That said,
when they retire from Active Duty service, they are a Veteran, and may also
continue to contribute their time to the Reserves or Guard.  While the treatment
of Veterans issues is a critical issue, it is somewhat separate from these
points, and something I would prefer to discuss separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;increased-tempo&#34;&gt;Increased Tempo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Drill Weekend&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Battle Assembly&lt;/em&gt; or whatever you call your weekend
requirements, is billed with the funny moniker, &lt;u&gt;&amp;hellip;one weekend a month&amp;hellip;&lt;/u&gt;
I would have to say that in my nearly 12 years in the Reserves, I have had
probably 4- or 5- weekends &lt;strong&gt;total&lt;/strong&gt; that fit that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                          11 years = 132 months
...one weekend a month... weekends = 4-5
                          the rest = 127-128 months
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the way that a weekend is counted is generally what you would call an
8-hour day.  In addition to saying these are billed as one-weekend affairs,
you&amp;rsquo;d think your day was a little longer.  I would say most weekends were at
least 12 hours, and I&amp;rsquo;ve gone without much more than 4-5 hours sleep in
a weekend in it&amp;rsquo;s entirety.  usually what we try to fit in these days.  It is
extremely difficult to meet the demands of the training requirements in an
8 hour day, and I would wager it is impossible without also requiring that
everyone does a bunch of work outside of the weekend to get things done (which
is also what happens, too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-constitutes-training&#34;&gt;What constitutes Training?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would you think fits in a normal weekend of training?  It is very often
completely different month-to-month, as we have a lot of general requirements to
meet in addition to the other training that we are required to fulfill.  Some of
these training events include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physical Fitness Tests (PT Test, PFT, etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marksmanship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MOS-based skills development (depends greatly on what your unit does)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team / Squad / Platoon / Company team building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandatory training (sexual assault / harrassment awareness, legal,
benefits, meet-and-greet with senior leadership)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say that it would be enough to just perform the MOS-based skills
development, but adding in these other requirements just makes things a whole
lot more difficult and time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extra-curricular-training&#34;&gt;Extra-curricular Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the &lt;strong&gt;minimum&lt;/strong&gt; requirements mentioned above, more often than
not, you may want to take on an additional training course or two in order to
stand out from your peers and potentially increase your knowledge and expertise
in your military occupational field/specialty (MOS). This is entirely possible,
but must happen completely outside of the time you&amp;rsquo;ve committed to the unit for
their training needs.  Your personal training needs are completely different,
and will require you to give up even more of your time.  There are a lot of
different training and extra time that you can commit yourself to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra Duty Service

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This would be where you would volunteer to help on a mini-mission of sorts,
something that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require an entire company to work on, but isn&amp;rsquo;t
something that can be done during the weekend.  It also could include
catch-up work that needed to be done but wasn&amp;rsquo;t complete before the
weekend, so could take a couple extra days out of your regular work-week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special Billet Training - leadership assignments that require additional training, such as:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equal Opportunity training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit Prevention Leader (qualified urinalysis test administrator training)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sexual Assault and Harassment representative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battle Assembly (learning to operate a unit&amp;rsquo;s admin house during
  a deployment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weapons Armorer (maintain the weapons)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership Advancement courses (often, these are required prerequisites before
you can even apply for a promotion to a Sergeant (SGT), Staff-Sergeant
(SSG), etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each one of these kinds of assignments can take anywhere from 1 to 4 weeks of
additional time during your year.  This is training that must be complete &lt;strong&gt;in
addition to&lt;/strong&gt; the unit&amp;rsquo;s required training.  If you have any hopes to be
a well-rounded leader, you will want to participate in these other training and
opportunities so you stand out a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-standard-training-cycles&#34;&gt;Non-Standard Training cycles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the above, you may start to realize that just meeting the &lt;u&gt;bare minimum&lt;/u&gt;
can be a big chore and requirement.  If you&amp;rsquo;re a leader for the unit, you&amp;rsquo;re
probably thinking &amp;ldquo;How the heck am I going to get this stuff done in
a weekend?&amp;rdquo; Well, the leaders have definitely thought about this, and what has
come down is to try to turn a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;hellip;one weekend a month&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt; into  &lt;strong&gt;&amp;hellip;three or
four days in a month&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A usual weekend for me is either a Friday - Sunday, or a Thursday through
Sunday.  This gives ample time to devote every hour of those days towards some
form of training.  We do a lot of training, but we also try to maximize the fact
that we have a captive audience, so we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;strong&gt;dare&lt;/strong&gt; send someone home after
a mere 8- or 12- hour day.  No, we will go from 5AM to 10PM every day to try to
fit in as much as possible.  If you can&amp;rsquo;t do the calculation in your head,
that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;u&gt;17 hours a day&lt;/u&gt;.  Long days, for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-does-supporting-the-troops-mean-anyway&#34;&gt;What does &amp;ldquo;Supporting the Troops&amp;rdquo; mean, anyway?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;strong&gt;Support the Troops&lt;/strong&gt; is very, VERY often, thrown about without any
regard for &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to do that.  I can only speak as a Reservist, so Active Duty
members may have a different opinion on the matter.  That said, I deal with
civilians daily, so I am often the face of the military for many people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to think that support means the same thing if you&amp;rsquo;re looking at it from
paternity / maternity leave, as well as different kinds of support you might
provide an employee when they&amp;rsquo;re going through a rough patch, such as a divorce,
death in the family, etc..  You might be a little more lenient on time away, or
you might try to provide them some things to make their days a little easier to
bear.  I think the same kind of empathy should be provided for someone who
chooses to commit &lt;strong&gt;one weekend a month&lt;/strong&gt;* to serving your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am certainly burned out after a long drill weekend, but I also have a very
hard time trying to stay on top of my career while also giving way to the
requirements of having to show up for my military obligations as well.  It&amp;rsquo;s
a tough set of things to do, and that isn&amp;rsquo;t even mentioning any kind of family
life you may have at home.  I know that my time with my family is critically
important to me, so having that flexibility to spend time with them is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;benefits-for-reservists&#34;&gt;Benefits for Reservists&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the benefits I look at as a potential employee, none stands out more than
whether you have any policy defined &lt;strong&gt;at all&lt;/strong&gt; for drilling members of the
military.  These benefts vary, but generally speaking, the biggest one is
simply:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;salary-continuity&#34;&gt;Salary Continuity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes all &lt;em&gt;training&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;monthly drill weekends&lt;/em&gt;, activation (when
necessary), and additional training as required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;make it obvious that your employment isn&amp;rsquo;t in jeopardy if you choose to do more
than the minimum required by contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, being able to provide continuity to your salary and family&amp;rsquo;s life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;avoid-bean-counting&#34;&gt;Avoid Bean Counting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that there are companies that are willing to provide that above
requirement, but they may do so on a limited basis.  They may allot X days
a month or a year to contribute to this fund, but no more.  Given what I have
said above, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s being honest about what your average military
Reservist is having to contribute, and it forces them to choose between being
a mediocre member of the military to one of the better ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe there should be any limitation to the time spent away.  If you
believe they are valuable as an employee, it is because of what they do, not in
spite of it.  It is probably difficult to compensate for someone that is not
there, and doubly so when you may have to hire someone to backfill for when
you&amp;rsquo;re out.  However, I think you hired the person because of their skills and
ability, so you should recognize that you&amp;rsquo;re essentially paying a small tax on
the benefit of having someone of that calibur working with your company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>